Prince Yu.
الأمير يو.
Hush.
صه.
Why didn't you tell me?
لماذا لم تخبرني
You made me feed mosquitoes here in the middle of the night.
جعلتني أطعم البعوض هنا في منتصف الليل.
I just want to enjoy the moon
أنا فقط أريد أن أستمتع بالقمر
with you.
معك.
and see the stars.
ونرى النجوم.
Right?
حق؟
Watching the moon
مشاهدة القمر
Look at the stars.
انظر الى النجوم.
Yes.
نعم.
Okay, I promise
حسنًا ، أعدك
I'll beat you to death.
سوف أضربك حتى الموت.
Madam, calm down.
سيدتي ، اهدئي.
Be gentle and virtuous.
كن لطيفًا وفاضلًا.
Put on your clothes.
ارتدي ملابسك.
Don't catch a cold.
لا تصاب بنزلة برد.
It's not cold.
انها ليست باردة.
It's so hot.
إنه ساخن جدا.
I finally fooled you.
لقد خدعتك أخيرًا.
To the left.
إلى اليسار.
Left.
اليسار.
After hanging the lanterns,
بعد تعليق الفوانيس ،
and clean the yard.
وتنظيف الفناء.
The Lantern Festival is in two days.
مهرجان الفوانيس في يومين.
We need to fix it as soon as possible.
نحن بحاجة إلى إصلاحه في أقرب وقت ممكن.
Yes.
نعم.
Master! Master!
يتقن!  يتقن!
You came back late last night.
لقد عدت في وقت متأخر من الليلة الماضية.
Why don't you sleep more today?
لماذا لا تنام أكثر اليوم؟
It doesn't matter. By the way,
لا يهم.  على فكرة،
Tell the kitchen
أخبر المطبخ
to make a bowl of porridge for Madam
لعمل وعاء من العصيدة سيدتي
Yes.
نعم.
It's good.
إنه جيد.
Chuntao.
تشونتاو.
What are you holding?
ماذا تحمل؟
It's a mask I prepared for Lantern Festival.
إنه قناع أعددته لمهرجان الفوانيس.
Masks?
أقنعة؟
A mask for Lantern Festival?
قناع لمهرجان الفوانيس؟
Here's the thing.
هنا الحاجة.
There is a custom at Lantern Festival.
هناك عادة في مهرجان المصابيح.
Many girls wear masks
ترتدي العديد من الفتيات الأقنعة
confess their love to the man they love.
يعترفون بحبهم للرجل الذي يحبونه.
Even if I was rejected,
حتى لو تم رفضي ،
I won't feel awkward.
لن أشعر بالحرج.
I lost face.
لقد فقدت وجهي.
I see.
أرى.
It's quite scientific.
إنه علمي تمامًا.
Madam.
سيدتي.
Master asked the kitchen
سأل سيد المطبخ
the breakfast is ready.
الفطور جاهز.
Okay.
تمام.
I'll be right there.
سأكون هناك.
Madam, Master
سيدتي ، معلمة
is so sweet.
حلو جدا.
I'm jealous.
أنا غيران.
Thank you for sending it back.
شكرا لك على إعادته.
I thought the painting
اعتقدت اللوحة
was sent to the palace.
تم إرساله إلى القصر.
Since I promised Madam Sun,
منذ أن وعدت سيدتي صن ،
I can't go back on my word.
لا أستطيع التراجع عن كلامي.
Please understand.
من فضلك إفهم.
The painting of mountains and rivers
لوحة الجبال والأنهار
my years of hard work.
سنوات عملي الشاق.
I don't want it to be stolen by others.
لا أريد أن يسرقها الآخرون.
I understand.
أفهم.
But since Madam Sun thinks
لكن بما أن سيدتي صن تعتقد
the Mountains and Rivers Scroll is in the palace,
لفافة الجبال والأنهار في القصر ،
Maybe others will misunderstand.
ربما يسيء الآخرون الفهم.
Thank you for your advice.
شكرا لك على نصيحتك.
You're welcome, Madam Sun.
اهلا وسهلا سيدتي صن.
Actually, I came here
في الواقع ، جئت إلى هنا
to discuss with Madam Sun.
للمناقشة مع سيدتي صن.
My wife is pregnant.
زوجتي حامل.
I'm afraid I can't continue to learn embroidery
أخشى أنني لا أستطيع الاستمرار في تعلم التطريز
with Madam Sun.
مع سيدتي صن.
It doesn't matter.
لا يهم.
You can call me anytime
بامكانك الاتصال بي في اي وقت
you can call me anytime.
بامكانك الاتصال بي في اي وقت.
Congratulations.
تهانينا.
Thank you, Madam Sun.
شكرا سيدتي صن.
I'll take my leave.
سآخذ إجازتي.
Please wait.
يرجى الانتظار.
Xiu.
شيوى.
I misunderstood you.
لقد أسأت فهمك.
This is a token of my apology.
هذا هو عربون اعتذاري.
I hope you and your wife
أتمنى لك ولزوجتك
and grow old together.
ونكبر معًا.
Mrs. Sun and I
السيدة صن وأنا
Mrs. Sun and I will accept it.
السيدة صن وأنا سوف نقبل ذلك.
Take it.
خذها.
Thank you.
شكرًا لك.
Ladies, have a look.
سيداتي القوا نظرة.
Madam, this mask is so beautiful.
سيدتي ، هذا القناع جميل جدا.
Have you decided
هل قررت
to confess to Master at Lantern Festival?
للاعتراف بالماجستير في مهرجان الفوانيس؟
It's a secret.
إنه سر.
Chuntao.
تشونتاو.
We're on the same side.
نحن في نفس الجانب.
Don’t tell anyone.
لا تخبر أحدا.
There are so many people in Xinghai City.
هناك الكثير من الناس في مدينة Xinghai.
Will Prince Yu
ويل برينس يو
receive a bunch of girls' confessions?
تلقي مجموعة من اعترافات الفتيات؟
Well...
نحن سوف...
It's possible.
انه ممكن.
Don't worry.
لا تقلق.
Master won't
سيد لا
accept other women's confession.
قبول اعتراف النساء الأخريات.
Wearing a mask,
يرتدي قناع ،
who can see who is the real one?
من يرى من هو الحقيقي؟
Fireworks.
العاب ناريه.
No.
لا.
I have to think of something different.
يجب أن أفكر في شيء مختلف.
Fireworks! Fireworks!
العاب ناريه!  العاب ناريه!
All kinds of fireworks are cheap.
جميع أنواع الألعاب النارية رخيصة.
Good quality.
جودة جيدة.
Don't miss it.
لا تفوتها.
Miss.
يفتقد.
Are you buying fireworks?
هل تشتري العاب ناريه؟
How much?
كم ثمن؟
30 taels of silver
30 تايل من الفضة
The big one is 100 taels
الكبير هو 100 تيل
That big 500 taels of silver
تلك الـ500 تيل الكبيرة من الفضة
So expensive?
غالي جدا؟
Miss, Lantern Festival is
ملكة جمال ، مهرجان المصابيح
the annual festival of the Star State.
المهرجان السنوي لستار ستيت.
The whole street is at the same price.
الشارع كله بنفس السعر.
If you buy it expensive, I'll return it.
إذا اشتريتها باهظة الثمن ، فسأعيدها.
These fireworks vendors
هؤلاء الباعة الألعاب النارية
are getting more and more shameless.
يزدادون وقحًا أكثر فأكثر.
Bah! The price is higher every year.
باه!  السعر أعلى كل عام.
I'd rather make fireworks myself.
أفضل صنع الألعاب النارية بنفسي.
Only ten taels of silver
فقط عشرة تايل من الفضة
to make fireworks for hundreds of taels.
لصنع ألعاب نارية لمئات التيل.
But they are strict now.
لكنهم صارمون الآن.
I can't buy those materials.
لا يمكنني شراء تلك المواد.
Don't worry. I have this.
لا تقلق.  لدي هذا.
I can buy anything.
يمكنني شراء أي شيء.
Madam.
سيدتي.
Hurry, send it back to others.
على عجل ، أرسلها إلى الآخرين.
You can borrow it.
يمكنك استعارته.
Let's buy ingredients to make fireworks.
لنشتري المكونات لصنع الألعاب النارية.
It's better than that vendor.
إنه أفضل من ذلك البائع.
Make fireworks yourself.
اصنع الألعاب النارية بنفسك.
Miss.
يفتقد.
Are you still buying fireworks?
هل ما زلت تشتري الألعاب النارية؟
If you buy,
اذا اشتريت،
I'll give you a discount.
سأعطيك خصمًا.
These fireworks are the most common.
هذه الألعاب النارية هي الأكثر شيوعًا.
I have to find a way
يجب أن أجد طريقة
to make unique fireworks.
لصنع ألعاب نارية فريدة.
Let us become
دعونا نصبح
the most beautiful boy at the lantern party.
اجمل فتى في حفلة الفانوس.
No.
لا.
Let's go.
لنذهب.
I'll give you a discount.
سأعطيك خصمًا.
Your Highness.
صاحب السمو.
Why are you looking for Zi Yu so early in the morning?
لماذا تبحث عن زي يو في وقت مبكر جدًا من الصباح؟
Father was seriously ill yesterday.
كان الأب مريضا جدا أمس.
The imperial physicians were helpless.
كان الأطباء الإمبراطوريون عاجزين.
You usually keep rare herbs.
عادة ما تحتفظ بالأعشاب النادرة.
Can I borrow it for Father to recuperate?
هل يمكنني استعارته لأبي للتعافي؟
He suddenly got seriously ill.
فجأة أصيب بمرض خطير.
Your Highness.
صاحب السمو.
The most important thing now is not the medicine.
الشيء الأكثر أهمية الآن ليس الدواء.
but the Sixth Prince.
لكن الأمير السادس.
Sixth Brother.
الأخ السادس.
The 6th Prince has always coveted the position of the Eastern Palace.
لطالما رغب الأمير السادس في منصب القصر الشرقي.
This imprisonment
هذا السجن
to his officials.
لمسؤوليه.
Besides, regarding the landscape painting,
الى جانب ذلك ، فيما يتعلق برسم المناظر الطبيعية ،
His Majesty is furious.
جلالة الملك غاضب.
If His Majesty is sick now,
إذا كان جلالته مريضا الآن ،
there is only one possibility.
هناك احتمال واحد فقط.
Zi Yu means
زي يو يعني
Sixth Brother is going to rebel?
الأخ السادس ذاهب إلى التمرد؟
If we don't rebel this time,
إذا لم نتمرد هذه المرة ،
he won't have a chance to do so in the future.
لن يكون لديه فرصة للقيام بذلك في المستقبل.
If you don't believe me,
إذا كنت لا تصدقني ،
let's find a way
دعونا نجد طريقة
and we'll know.
وسنعرف.